Adam Juraszek



adam.a.juraszek@googlemail.com

https://github.com/crawdaddie

Backend engineer with 6 years of experience passionate about experimentation and clean solutions.

I work closely with product stakeholders to ensure alignment with user needs, and try to learn as much as possible from every member of a team I interact with. I am most interested in roles where I can build on my technical leadership, and work on distributed, data-intensive cloud-native systems.



Experience

Curation Corporation - Senior backend engineer

London - 6/2021 - present

- development of internal tools supporting ESG experts in synthesising business intelligence from a wide variety of news sources
- implemented new features for creating automated email briefings which reduced the time taken to create briefings by 84% compared to previous non-integrated workflows
- maintenance and tuning of data pipelines which process 3 million articles a day and push them to different search indices
- deployment of NLP models as FastAPI services for purposes of abstractive summarisation and entity extraction
- implemented several DX improvements:
 - · added typescript, increased modularity and inversion of control
 - increased test-coverage and added backend test-suites to CI pipelines
 - utilities for repeatable fully-seeded test deployments
 - \bullet optimisation and parallelisation of CI/CD pipelines
 - which improved confidence in delivery, code quality and cadence

Birdie - Full-stack developer

London - 11/2019 - 2/2021

- development of various frontend and backend components of Birdie's elderly care software ecosystem
- improved performance of backend services by adding permissions-caching layers
- helped improve system consistency by implementing utilities for optimistic concurrency control

Vectary - 3D developer

Bratislava - 06/2019 - 10/2019

- refactoring and development of Vectary's 3D-modelling engine (typescript and THREE.js)
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ making detailed optimisations for browser performance through extensive use of the v8 profiler
- · developing robust importer/exporter tools for proprietary 3D file formats

Subdigital - software developer

Bratislava - 08/2018 - 06/2019

- ${f \cdot}$ design and development of hardware ${f \cdot}$ software components of digitally-enhanced architectural models and installations
- building prototypes that helped Subdigital develop new clients
- mathematical modelling to optimise custom tools in Grasshopper for Rhino

Lab.SNG - software developer

Bratislava - 01/2018 - 06/2019

- development of the web-umenia search API for the archives of the Slovak National Gallery
- introduced Docker to team workflow

Kiwi.com - Junior Python Developer

Bratislava - 11/2016 - 12/2017

development of internal HR software using Django

Education

Institute of Sonology, Koninklijk Conservatorium

MMus

- studied music computing, design and development of software synthesis and music
- performance systems, history and theory of algorithmic music and sound studies gave many concerts of my own music, often using self-built tools

One Year Cursus Den Haag - 2013 - 2014

• music technology and programming for music

Imperial College - B.Sc Math

London - 2007 - 2010

Den Haag - 2014 - 2016

specialising in Topology but also studied Linear Algebra and Computational Methods

Skills

High Fluency

- Typescript, Node.js, NestJS
- Python, FastApi
- graphql
- PostgreSQL, SQL Server
- kubernetes, Docker
- ElasticSearch
- React

Intermediate Fluency

- AW
- Flask, numpy
- HTML, CSS

Side Interests

- SuperCollider, Max/MSP, audio programming
- Rust, Go

Selected Projects

- constraint problem solver gui (Octeract, London -2/2021 - 6/2021)
 - python environments which offer interactive solving of MINLP problems
- browser development environment and REPL communicating with python environments over websockets
- Supercollider tools
- project framework for algorithmic composition
- missing import statement
- gui event sequencer
- Múzeum Slovenských národných rád, Myjava -03/2019 Audio installation with ultrasonic distance sensors and arduino microcontrollers
- Keys, Trauma Bar und Kino, Berlin - 02/2019 Live-coding music performance at algorave
- Pohoda Klub stage, Trenčín - 06/2018 Live music performance at a major Slovak music festival